MAN ON RADIO:
Men, are you over 40?
When you wake up in the morning,
do you feel tired and rundown?
Do you have that
listless feeling?
(CHANGES STATION)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALARM RINGING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Jefferies.
GUNNISON:
Congratulations, Jeff.
For what?
For getting rid of that cast.
Who said I was
getting rid of it?
This is Wednesday.
Seven weeks from the day
you broke your leg. Yes or no?
Gunnison, how did you ever get to be such
a big editor with such a small memory?
Thrift, industry
and hard work.
And catching the publisher
with his secretary.
Did I get the wrong day?
No.
No, wrong week.
Next Wednesday I emerge
from this plaster cocoon.
That's too bad, Jeff.
Well, I guess I can't
be lucky every day.
Forget I called.
Yeah, I sure feel sorry
for you, Gunnison.
Must be rough on you thinking of me
wearing this cast for another whole week.
That one week is gonna cost me
my best photographer
and you a big assignment.
Where?
There's no point in
even talking about it.
Oh, come on, come on. Where?
Kashmir.
Got a code tip
from the bureau chief this morning.
The place is about
to go up in smoke.
What did I tell you? Didn't I tell you
that's the next place to watch?
You did.
Okay. When do I leave?
Half-hour? Hour?
With that cast on? You don't.
Stop sounding stuffy.
I can take pictures from a jeep
or a water buffalo, if necessary.
You're too valuable to the magazine
for us to play around with.
I'll send Morgan or Lambert.
Morgan or Lambert.
That's fine.
I get myself
half-killed for you,
and you reward me
by stealing my assignments.
I didn't ask you to stand in the middle
of that automobile racetrack.
You asked for something
dramatically different. You got it.
So did you. Goodbye, Jeff.
Now wait a minute, Gunnison.
You've got to get me out of here.
Six weeks sitting in
a two-room apartment
with nothing to do but look out
the window at the neighbors.
Bye, Jeff.
No, Gunnison, I...
If you don't pull me out
of this swamp of boredom,
I'm gonna do
something drastic.
Like what?
"Like what?"
I'm gonna get married.
And then I'll never
be able to go anywhere.
It's about time
you got married,
before you turn into a lonesome
and bitter old man.
Yeah, can't you just see me?
Rushing home to
a hot apartment
to listen to the automatic laundry
and the electric dishwasher
and the garbage disposal
and the nagging wife.
Jeff, wives don't nag
anymore, they discuss.
Is that so? Is that so?
Well, maybe in the high-rent
district they discuss.
In my neighborhood,
they still nag.
Yeah? Well, you know best.
I'll call you later, Jeff.
Yeah, have some good news
the next time, huh?
Good morning.
I said, "Good morning!"
Oh, good morning.
Say, I wouldn't dig
so deep if I were you.
You're giving them
far too much water.
Why don't you shut up?
Well!
I do declare.
New York State sentence for a Peeping Tom is
six months in the workhouse.
Oh, hello, Stella.
And they got no windows
in the workhouse.
You know, in the old days, they used
to put your eyes out with a red-hot poker.
Any of those bikini bombshells
you're always watching worth a red-hot poker?
Oh, dear. We've become
a race of Peeping Toms.
What people ought to do is get outside
their own house and look in for a change.
Yes, sir.
How's that for a bit
of homespun philosophy?
Reader's Digest,
April, 1939.
- Well, I only quote from the best.
- Yeah.
You don't have to take my
temperature this morning.
Quiet. See if you
can break 100.
You know, I should have
been a gypsy fortune-teller
instead of
an insurance-company nurse.
I got a nose for trouble.
Can smell it ten miles away.
You heard of that market crash in '29?
I predicted that.
(MUMBLING)
Just how did you do that, Stella?
Oh, simple.
I was nursing
a director of General Motors.
"Kidney ailment," they said.
"Nerves," I said.
Then I asked myself, "What's General Motors
got to be nervous about?"
"Overproduction," I says.
"Collapse."
When General Motors has to
go to the bathroom 10 times a day,
the whole country's
ready to let go.
You know, Stella,
in economics,
a kidney ailment has no relationship
to the stock market.
None whatsoever.
Crashed, didn't it?
I can smell trouble right here
in this apartment.
First you smash your leg, then you
get to looking out the window,
see things you shouldn't see.
Trouble.
I can see you in court now,
surrounded by a bunch of lawyers
in double-breasted suits.
You're pleading. You say, "Judge, it was only
a little bit of innocent fun.
"I love my neighbors,
like a father."
And the judge says,
"Well, congratulations.
"You've just given birth
to three years in Dannemora."
Right now I'd welcome
trouble, you know.
You've got a
hormone deficiency.
How can you tell
from a thermometer?
Those bathing beauties
you've been watching
haven't raised your temperature
one degree in a month.
Here we go.
One more week.
No, I think you're right. I think
there is gonna be trouble around here.
I knew it.
Ooh!
Do you ever heat that stuff?
Gives your circulation
something to fight.
Oh, I see.
What kind of trouble?
Lisa Fremont.
You kidding?
She's a beautiful young girl, and you're
a reasonably healthy young man.
She expects me to marry her.
That's normal.
I don't want to.
That's abnormal.
I just... I'm not
ready for marriage.
Every man's ready for marriage
when the right girl comes along.
And Lisa Fremont is the right girl
for any man with half a brain
who can get one eye open.
She's all right.
- What'd you do, have a fight?
- No.
Father loading
up the shotgun?
What?
Please, Stella.
It's happened
before, you know.
Some of the world's
happiest marriages
have started "under the gun,"
as you might say.
No, she's just not
the girl for me.
Yeah, she's only perfect.
She's too perfect. She's too talented.
She's too beautiful. She's too sophisticated.
She's too everything
but what I want.
Is what you want something
you can discuss?
What? It's very
simple, Stella.
She belongs to that rarefied atmosphere
of Park Avenue, you know.
Expensive restaurants and
literary cocktail parties.
People with sense belong
wherever they're put.
Can you imagine her traveling
around the world with a camera bum
who never has more than
a week's salary in the bank?
If she was only ordinary.
You never gonna get married?
I'll probably get married one
of these days,
but when I do, it's gonna be
to someone who thinks of life
not just as a new dress
and a lobster dinner
or latest scandal.
I need a woman who's
willing to... Hold it.
Who's willing to go anywhere
and do anything and love it.
So the honest thing for me to do is
just call the whole thing off.
Let her find somebody else.
Yeah, I can hear you now.
"Get out of my life,
you perfectly wonderful woman.
"You're too good for me."
Look, Mr. Jefferies,
I'm not an educated woman,
but I can tell you one thing.
When a man and a woman see
each other and like each other,
they ought to come together, wham,
like a couple of taxis on Broadway,
and not sit around analyzing each other
like two specimens in a bottle.
There's an intelligent way
to approach marriage.
Intelligence.
Nothing has caused the human race
so much trouble as intelligence.
(SCOFFS) Modern marriage.
No, we've progressed
emotionally.
Baloney.
Once it was, "See somebody,
get excited, get married."
Now it's, "Read a lot of books,
fence with a lot of four-syllable words,
"psychoanalyze each other
"until you can't tell
the difference between
"a petting party and
a civil service exam."
People have different
emotional levels...
When I married Myles, we were both
a couple of maladjusted misfits.
We are still maladjusted misfits,
and we have loved every minute of it.
Well, that's fine, Stella.
Now, would you fix me
a sandwich, please?
Yes, I will.
And I'll spread a little common
sense on the bread.
Lisa's loaded to her fingertips
with love for you.
I got two words of advice
for you. Marry her.
She pay you much?
Oh!
There.
- Here's the key.
- Thank you.
Well, if you want
anything, just ring.
Honey. Come on.
Got to carry you
over the threshold.
Window shopper.
(PIANO PLAYING)
(WOMAN SINGING)
How's your leg?
It hurts a little.
And your stomach?
Empty as a football.
And your love life?
Not too active.
Anything else bothering you?
Mmm-hmm.
Who are you?
Reading from top
to bottom, Lisa
Carol
Fremont.
Is this the Lisa Fremont who never wears
the same dress twice?
Only because it's
expected of her.
It's right off the Paris plane.
Do you think it'll sell?
That depends on the quote,
you know. Let's see now.
There's the airplane ticket over and import
duties, hidden taxes, profit markup...
A steal at $1,100.
Eleven hundred?
They ought to list that dress
on the stock exchange.
Why, we sell a dozen
a day in this price range.
Who buys them,
tax collectors?
Even if I had to pay, it would be
worth it. Just for the occasion.
Why, is something big
going on somewhere?
It's going on right here.
It's a big night.
It's just an old run-of-the-mill Wednesday.
The calendar's full of them.
It's opening night of the last depressing week
of L.B. Jefferies in a cast.
Well, I haven't noticed a big demand
for tickets or anything.
That's because I
bought out the house.
You know, this cigarette box has
seen better days.
I picked that up in Shanghai,
which has also seen better days.
It's cracked and you never use it.
It's too ornate.
I'm sending up a plain, flat, silver one
with just your initials engraved.
That's no way to spend your
hard-earned money.
Well, I wanted to.
Oh!
What would you think of starting off
with dinner at '21'?
You have, perhaps, an
ambulance downstairs?
No, better than that. '21.'
Thank you for waiting, Carl.
The kitchen's right there on the left.
Oh, I'll take the wine.
- Good evening, Mr. Jefferies.
- Carl.
Just put everything in the oven,
Carl, on low.
- Yes, madam.
- Let's open the wine now.
JEFF: All right.
It's a Montrachet.
A great big glassful.
There's a corkscrew right over there.
Here, I'll do it.
Big enough?
Yeah, they're fine.
I can't think of anything more boring
or tiresome than what you've been through,
- and the last week must be the hardest.
- Let me, sir.
All right.
Yeah, I want to get this thing off
and get moving.
Well, I'm going to make this
a week you'll never forget.
Fine, thanks.
Just a minute, Carl.
This will take care
of the taxi as well.
Thank you, Miss Fremont.
Have a pleasant dinner,
Mr. Jefferies.
All right. Good night.
Good night.
(SIGHS) What a day I've had.
Are you tired?
Not a bit.
I was all morning
in a sales meeting,
then I had to dash to the Waldorf
for a quick drink with Madame Dufresne,
who's just over from Paris
with some spy reports.
And then I had to go to '21' and have lunch
with the Harper's Bazaar people.
And that's when
I ordered dinner.
Then I had two fall showings
20 blocks apart.
Then I had to have a cocktail
with Leland and Slim Hayward.
We're trying to
get his new show.
And then I had to
dash back and change.
Well, now, tell me. Tell me.
Now, what was Mrs. Hayward wearing?
- Oh, she looked wonderfully cool.
- She did.
She had on the most
divine Italian hand-print
- mousseline de soie...
- Oh, Italian?
- Oh, you.
- Italian. Imagine.
To think I planted three nice items
in the columns about you today.
You did?
You can't buy that
kind of publicity.
I know.
Someday you may want to open up
a studio of your own here.
How would I run it
from, say, Pakistan?
Jeff...
Isn't it time you came home?
You could pick your assignment.
I wish there
was one I wanted.
Make the one you want.
- You mean leave the magazine?
- Yes.
For what?
For yourself and me.
I could get you a dozen
assignments tomorrow.
Don't laugh. I could do it.
That's what I'm afraid of.
Can you see me driving down
to the fashion salon in a jeep,
wearing combat boots
and a three-day beard?
Wouldn't that make a hit?
I could see you looking very handsome
and successful in a dark blue flannel suit.
Let's stop talking
nonsense, shall we?
Hmm?
Guess I'd better start
setting up for dinner.
MAN: (SINGING)
To see you is to love you
And I see you everywhere
In the sunrise
In the moon glow
Any place I look you're there
To see you is to want you
And I see you all the time
On a sidewalk
In a doorway
On the lonely stairs I climb
Someday let me show you
How happy endings start
You'll find how well
I know you
'Cause to know you at all
Is to know you by heart
To see you is to love you
And you're never out of sight
And I love you
and I'll see you
In the same old dream
Tonight
Miss Lonelyheart.
At least that's something
you'll never have to worry about.
Oh?
You can see my apartment from here,
all the way up on 63rd Street?
No, not exactly, but we have
a little apartment here
that's probably about
as popular as yours.
You remember, of course,
Miss Torso, the ballet dancer?
She's like a queen bee
with her pick of the drones.
(ALL CHATTERING)
LISA: I'd say she's doing
a woman's hardest job. Juggling wolves.
Thank you.
Well, she picked the most
prosperous-looking one.
She's not in love with him
or any of them.
Oh, how can you
tell that from here?
You said it resembled
my apartment, didn't you?
I hope they're
cooked this time.
(INAUDIBLE)
(WOMAN CHATTERING)
(PIANO PLAYING)
Where's that wonderful
music coming from?
Some songwriter over there
in the studio apartment.
Wow!
He lives alone. Probably
had a very unhappy marriage.
Oh, it's enchanting.
It's almost as if it were being
written especially for us.
Hmm.
No wonder he's having so much
trouble with it.
At least you can't say
the dinner isn't right.
Lisa, it's perfect.
As always.
There can't be that much difference
between people and the way they live.
We all eat, talk,
drink, laugh, wear clothes.
Well, now look...
If you're saying all this because you don't
want to tell me the truth,
because you're hiding something
from me, then maybe I can understand.
I'm not hiding anything.
It's just that...
It doesn't make sense.
What's so different about it here
from over there or anyplace you go
that one person couldn't live
in both places just as easily?
Some people can.
Now, if you'll just let me...
What is it but traveling from one place
to another, taking pictures?
It's just like being a tourist
on an endless vacation.
Okay.
Now that's your opinion.
You're entitled to it.
Now, let me give you my side.
It's ridiculous to say that
it can only be done
by a special, private little group
of anointed people.
I made a simple statement,
a true statement,
but I can back it up if you'd
just shut up for a minute.
If your opinion is as rude as your manner,
I don't think I care to hear it.
Oh, come on now. Simmer down.
I can't fit in here.
You can't fit in there.
I mean, according to you, people should be born,
live and die on the same spot!
Shut up!
Did you ever eat
fish heads and rice?
Of course not.
Well, you might have
to if you went with me.
Did you ever try to keep warm in a C-54
at 15,000 feet, 20 degrees below zero?
Oh, I do it all the time. Whenever I have
a few minutes after lunch.
Did you ever get shot at?
Did you ever get run over?
Did you ever get
sandbagged at night
because somebody got unfavorable publicity
from your camera?
Did you ever... Those high heels,
they'll be great in the jungle.
And the nylons and
those six-ounce lingerie.
- Three.
- All right, three.
They'll make a big hit in Finland,
just before you freeze to death.
Well, if there's one thing I know,
it's how to wear the proper clothes.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, try and find a raincoat in Brazil,
even when it isn't raining.
Lisa, in this job
you carry one suitcase.
Your home is
the available transportation.
You don't sleep very much.
You bathe less.
And sometimes
the food that you eat
is made from things that you couldn't
even look at when they're alive.
Jeff, you don't have to be deliberately repulsive
just to impress me I'm wrong.
Deliberately repulsive?
I'm just trying to make it sound good.
You just have to face it, Lisa,
you're not meant for that kind of a life.
Few people are.
You're too stubborn
to argue with.
I'm not stubborn.
I'm just truthful.
I know, a lesser man would have told me
it was one long holiday,
and I would have been awakened
to a rude disillusionment.
Oh, well now, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
If you want to get vicious on this thing,
I'd be very happy to accommodate you.
No, I don't particularly
want that.
So that's it?
You won't stay here,
and I can't go with you.
It would be the wrong thing.
You don't think either one of us
could ever change?
Right now it doesn't seem so.
I'm in love with you. I don't care
what you do for a living.
I'd just like to be
part of it somehow.
It's deflating to find out
the only way I can be part of it
is to take out a subscription
to your magazine.
I guess I'm not the girl
I thought I was.
There's nothing wrong
with you, Lisa.
You've got this town
in the palm of your hand.
Not quite, it seems.
Goodbye, Jeff.
You mean good night.
I mean what I said.
Well, Lisa,
couldn't we just...
Uh...
Couldn't we just keep things
status quo?
Without any future?
When am I gonna
see you again?
Not for a long time.
At least
not until tomorrow night.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- WOMAN: Don't!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Hey! Rain.
Grab that. The rest of the blanket.
Wait, I'll get the clock.
Oh, no!
(ALARM RINGING)
Put it in, now.
Pull on it.
Let me do it.
In you go.
(EXCLAIMS)
No, you can't come in.
It's much too late.
No, no, not now. Get your foot
out of the way. No, I said good night.
What's that supposed to be,
ma'am?
It's called "Hunger."
You'd think the rain would have
cooled things off.
All it did was
make the heat wet.
That's it. That's it.
That's stiff one, right there.
Right there.
You know, the insurance company
would be much happier
if you'd sleep in bed at night instead of
in that wheelchair.
How'd you know?
Eyes are all bloodshot.
Must have been watching out
that window for hours.
Yeah, I was.
What are you gonna do if
one of them catches you?
It depends which one.
Miss Torso, for example...
You keep your mind off her.
She sure is the "Eat,
drink and be merry" girl.
Yeah, she'll wind up fat,
alcoholic and miserable.
Yeah.
Speaking of misery, poor Miss Lonelyheart.
She drank herself to sleep again, alone.
Poor soul. Oh, well.
Maybe one day she'll
find her happiness.
Yeah, and some man
will lose his.
Isn't there anybody in the neighborhood
who could cast an eye in her direction?
I don't know.
It just might be that the salesman
will be available soon.
Oh, him and his wife
splitting up?
I just can't figure it.
He went out several times last night
in the rain, carrying his sample case.
Well, he's a salesman,
isn't he?
What would he be selling
at 3:00 in the morning?
Flashlights.
Luminous dials for watches.
House numbers that light up.
I don't think so.
I think he was taking something out
of the apartment.
Uh-huh.
His personal effects.
He's gonna run out
on her, the coward.
Yeah.
Sometimes it's worse
to stay than it is to run.
Yeah, well, it takes a particularly low type
of man to do a thing like that.
How about this morning?
Any further developments?
The shades are all
drawn in the apartment.
- In this heat?
- Yeah.
Well, they're up now.
Get back! Get back!
Where do you want me to go?
Come on, get out of sight.
Get out of sight.
What is it?
What's the matter?
That salesman's looking out
of his window. You see?
Get back! He'll see you.
I'm not shy.
I've been looked at before.
That's no ordinary look.
That's the kind
of look a man gives
when he's afraid somebody
might be watching him.
(WHIMPERING)
Get away from there. Get away from there.
He'll be after you.
Go on, into the house.
Into the house.
(SHOOING)
Goodbye, Mr. Jefferies.
See you tomorrow.
Uh-huh.
And don't sleep in
that chair again.
Uh-huh.
"Uh-huh. Uh-huh."
Great conversationalist.
Stella.
Take those binoculars out of the case
and bring them here, will you?
Trouble. I can smell it.
I'll be glad when they crack that cast,
and I can get out of here.
Uh-huh.
(WOMAN WHISTLING)
(BARKING)
(WOMAN WHISTLING MELODY)
How far does a girl have
to go before you'll notice her?
Well, if she's pretty enough,
she doesn't have to go anywhere.
She just has to "be."
Well, ain't I?
Pay attention to me.
I'm not exactly on
the other side of the room.
Your mind is...
And when I want a man,
I want all of him.
Don't you ever
have any problems?
I have one now.
So do I.
Tell me about it.
Why...
Why would a man leave his apartment three times
on a rainy night with a suitcase,
and come back three times?
He likes the way his
wife welcomes him home.
No, no. No, no.
No, no. Not this
salesman's wife.
And why didn't he
go to work today?
Homework. It's
more interesting.
What's interesting
about a butcher knife
and a small saw
wrapped in newspaper? Hmm?
Nothing, thank heaven.
Why hasn't he been
in his wife's bedroom all day?
I wouldn't dare answer that.
Well, listen. I'll answer it, Lisa.
There's something terribly wrong.
And I'm afraid it's with me.
What do you think?
Something too
frightful to utter.
He went out a few minutes ago
in his undershirt, hasn't come back yet.
That'd be a terrible job
to tackle.
(PIANO PLAYING)
Just how would you start
to cut up a human body?
Jeff, I'll be honest with you.
You're beginning to scare me a little.
Jeff, did you hear what I said?
You're beginning to scare...
Shh! Shh!
He's coming back!
Jeff, if you could
only see yourself!
What's the matter?
Sitting around looking out of the window
to kill time is one thing,
but doing it the way you are,
with binoculars and wild opinions
about every little thing you see,
is diseased!
What, do you think I
consider it recreation?
I don't know what
you consider it,
but if you don't stop it,
I'm getting out of here.
What's the...
What is it you're
looking for?
I just want to find out what's the matter
with the salesman's wife, that's all.
Does that make me
sound like a madman?
What makes you think there's something
the matter with her?
A lot of things. She's an invalid.
She demands constant care.
Yet neither the husband or anybody else
has been in to see her all day. Why?
Maybe she died.
Where's the doctor?
Where's the undertaker?
She could be sleeping,
under sedatives.
He's in there now.
There's nothing to see.
There is something...
I've seen it through that window.
I've seen bickering
and family quarrels
and mysterious trips at night
and knives and saws and ropes.
And now, since last evening,
not a sign of the wife.
All right. Now you tell me
where she is.
- I don't know.
- What's she doing? Where is she?
Maybe he's leaving his wife.
I don't know. I don't care!
Lots of people have knives and saws
and ropes around their houses.
And lots of men don't speak
to their wives all day.
Lots of wives nag and men hate them
and trouble starts,
but very, very few of them end up in murder,
if that's what you're thinking.
It's pretty hard for you to keep away
from that word, isn't it?
- You could see all that he did, couldn't you?
- Of course...
You could see
because the shades were up
and he walked along the corridor
and the street and the backyard.
I've seen him in the backyard,
fixing the flowers...
Oh, Jeff, do you think a murderer
would let you see all that?
That he wouldn't pull the shades down
and hide behind them?
Just where he's being clever.
He's being nonchalant about it.
And that's where you're not
being clever.
A murderer would never parade his crime
in front of an open window.
Why not?
Why, for all you know,
there's probably something a lot more
sinister going on behind those windows.
Where?
Oh!
(CHUCKLES)
No comment.
Let's start from
the beginning again, Jeff.
Tell me everything you saw
and what you think it means.
(PHONE RINGS)
Yeah?
LISA: The name
on the second floor
rear mail box reads,
"Mr. and Mrs. Lars."
That's L-A-R-S.
Lars Thorwald.
What's the number of
the apartment house?
125 West 9th Street.
Thank you, dear.
Okay, chief.
What's my next assignment?
Just go home.
All right,
but what's he doing now?
He's just sitting
in the living room in the dark.
Hasn't gone near the bedroom.
Now you go home
and get some sleep.
- Good night.
DOYLE: All right.
What's it all about, Jeff?
Now look, Doyle, it's just something
I can't tell you over the telephone.
You have to be here
and see the whole setup.
Important, huh?
Well, it's probably
nothing important at all.
It's just a little neighborhood murder,
that's all.
Did you say "murder," Jeff?
Yes, as a matter of fact,
I did say "murder."
Oh, come now.
My only thought was throwing
a little business your way, that's all.
I figured a good detective would jump
at the chance of something to detect.
- I'm not working.
- What?
This happens to
be my day off.
Well, I usually took
my best pictures on my day off.
I'll drop by.
Okay, Doyle. All right.
As soon as you can.
Bless your heart, Stella.
Gee whiz, look at this.
I can't tell you
what a welcome sight this is.
No wonder your husband
still loves you.
- The police.
- What?
You called the police.
Well, not exactly.
Not an official call.
It's just an old friend of mine.
An old, ornery
friend of mine.
Just where do you
suppose he cut her up?
Of course. The bathtub.
That's the only place where he could
have washed away the blood.
He better get that trunk out
of there before it starts to leak.
WOMAN: Harry?
Look, look, Mr. Jefferies.
I thought Doyle would be here
by the time the trunk left,
or I'd have called the police.
Now we're gonna lose it.
- Hold everything.
- Don't do anything foolish.
I'm just gonna get the name off
that freight truck.
I'll keep an eye
on the alley.
Long distance.
You didn't see the killing or the body.
How do you know there was a murder?
Because everything this fellow's done
has been suspicious.
Trips at night in the rain, and knives
and saws and trunks with rope
and now this wife
that isn't there anymore.
I admit it all has a mysterious sound.
It could be any number of things.
Murder's the least plausible.
Doyle, don't tell me
he's an unemployed magician,
amusing the neighborhood with his sleight
of hand. Don't tell me that.
It's too obvious and stupid
a way to commit murder.
In full view of 50 windows?
Then sit over there
smoking a cigar,
waiting for the police
to come and pick him up?
All right, Officer, do your duty.
Go over and pick him up.
Jeff, you've got a lot to learn
about homicide.
Why, morons have
committed murder so shrewdly,
it's taken a hundred trained police minds
to catch them.
That salesman wouldn't just knock
his wife off after dinner
and toss her in the trunk
and put her in storage.
I'll bet it's been done.
Most everything's
been done, under panic.
This is
a thousand-to-one shot.
He's still sitting around the apartment.
That man's not panicked.
You think I made all this up?
Well, I think
you saw something.
There's probably a very simple
explanation for that.
For instance?
Wife took a trip.
His wife was sick in bed.
Yeah, so you told me.
Well, Jeff,
I've got to run along.
I won't report this to the department.
Let me poke into it a little on my own.
No sense in your getting a lot of
ridiculous publicity.
Thank you.
We know the wife is gone,
so I'll see if I can find out where.
Do that.
You had any headaches lately?
Not until you showed up.
It'll wear off,
along with the hallucinations.
See you around.
(DOG WHINING)
Get along.
(DOG BARKING)
He has a six months' lease.
Used up a little more than five
and a half months of it.
He's quiet, drinks,
but not to drunkenness.
Pays his bills promptly with money earned
as a costume jewelry salesman.
Wholesale.
Kept to himself. None of his neighbors
got close to him or his wife.
Yeah, well, I think they missed
their chance with her.
She never left
the apartment...
- Where is she? The icebox?
- ...until yesterday morning.
- What time?
- 6:00 a.m.
6:00 a.m.
I think that's about
the time I fell asleep.
Too bad.
Thorwalds were leaving their apartment
at just that time.
Feel a little foolish?
No, not yet.
How's your wife?
Oh, she's fine.
Who said they left then?
Who left where?
The Thorwalds,
at 6:00 in the morning.
Oh, the building superintendent
and two tenants.
Flat statements, no hesitation.
They jived with the letter.
Thorwalds were on their way
to the railroad station.
Well, now, Tom, how could anybody
possibly guess that?
What, did they have signs on their luggage,
saying, "Grand Central or bust?"
The superintendent met Thorwald
on his way back.
Thorwald told him that he'd put
his wife on a train to the country.
I see. I'd say this is a pretty
convenient guy, this superintendent.
Have you checked his bank
statements lately?
Huh?
Well, what good's
his information?
It's a secondhand version
of an unsupported story
by the murderer
himself, Thorwald.
Now did anybody actually see
the wife get on the train?
I hate to remind you,
but this all started because you said
she was murdered.
Now, did anyone, including you,
actually see her murdered?
What are you doing?
Are you interested in solving this case
or in making me look foolish?
Well, if possible, both.
Well, then, do a
good job of it.
Go over there
and search Thorwald's apartment.
It must be knee-deep
in evidence.
I can't do that.
Well, no, I don't mean right now,
but when he goes out for a drink,
or a paper, or something.
What he doesn't know won't hurt him.
I can't do that,
even if he isn't there.
What's he... Does he have a courtesy card
from the police department, or something?
Now don't get me mad.
Not even a detective can walk
into an apartment and search it.
If I were caught in there,
they'd have my badge within 10 minutes.
All right. Make sure
you don't get caught, that's all.
What? If you find something,
you've got a murderer,
and they don't care anything
about a couple of house rules.
If you don't find anything,
the fellow's clear.
At the risk of sounding stuffy, I'd like
to remind you of the Constitution
and the phrase, "Search warrant issued
by a judge
"who knows his Bill
of Rights verbatim."
He must ask for evidence.
Give him evidence.
Yeah, I can hear myself.
"Your Honor, I have a friend
who's an amateur sleuth.
"Well, the other night after having
a heavy dinner, he..."
He'd throw the New York State
penal code right in my face.
And there's six volumes.
You know, by tomorrow morning
there may not be any evidence left
over in that apartment.
You know that.
It's a detective's nightmare.
What do you need
before you can search?
Tell me. Now,
what do you need?
Bloody footsteps leading up
to the door?
One thing I don't need is heckling.
You called me and asked for help.
Now you're behaving
like a taxpayer.
How did we ever stand
each other in that plane
for three years
during the war?
I guess I'll go over to the railroad station
and check on Thorwald's story.
Oh, forget about the story.
Find the trunk.
Mrs. Thorwald's in it.
Oh, I almost forgot.
There was a postcard in
Thorwald's mailbox. It was
mailed 3:30 yesterday
afternoon from Merritsville.
That's 80 miles
north of here.
Message went, "Arrived okay.
Already feeling better.
"Love, Anna."
Oh...
Is that...
Anna... Is that
who I think it is?
Mrs. Thorwald.
Oh, so anything
you need, Jeff?
You might send me
a good detective.
(SIGHS)
(WOMAN WHISTLING MELODY)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(CHATTERING)
WOMAN: (SINGING)
Many dreams ago
I dreamed many dreams
Waiting for my true love
To appear
Though each night it seems
- (BOTH CHATTERING)
- Someone filled my dreams
- (CAR HORN BLARING)
- Still the face
That I kissed wasn't clear
So I let my heart dance
To many sweet refrains
But now just one song
And just one dream remains
That one song is you
And at last I know
You're the one I dreamed of
Many dreams ago
- MRS. DOYLE: Hello?
- Hello, Miss Doyle?
Yes?
This is Jeff again.
Has Tom come in yet?
Not yet, Jeff.
You mean you haven't
even heard from him?
Not a word. Is it something
really important, Jeff?
Yeah, I'm afraid it is, Tess.
I'll have him call the moment
I hear from him.
No, no, don't
bother to do that.
Just have him get over here
as soon as he can.
Looks like Thorwald's
pulling out tonight.
Who's Thorwald?
He'll know, he'll know.
And Thorwald's a man,
Tess, don't worry.
- (CHUCKLES) Good night, you idiot.
- Good night.
Long distance again.
(INAUDIBLE)
MAN: There's somebody
at the door.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
- Hi.
- Hello.
Hello.
What'd you do to your hair?
- Oh, well, I just sort of...
- Take a look at Thorwald.
He's getting ready to pull out
for good. Look at him.
He doesn't seem
to be in any hurry.
He's been laying out all his things
on one of the beds.
Shirts, suits, coats, socks.
Even his wife's...
That alligator handbag
- his wife had on the bedpost.
- What about it?
He had it hidden in the dresser.
At least, it was there.
He took it out, went to the telephone
and made a long-distance call.
He had his wife's jewelry
in the handbag.
Seemed worried about it.
Asked somebody's advice over
the telephone.
Someone not his wife.
Well, I never saw
him ask her for advice.
She volunteered plenty, but I never
saw him ask her for any.
I wonder where he's going.
I don't know.
Suppose he doesn't come
back again?
He'll be back.
His things are still there.
Well, I guess it's safe
to put on some lights now.
No, not yet!
Okay, you can turn it on now.
He must have gone someplace to the right.
All day long, I've been trying
to keep my mind on my work.
Thinking about Thorwald?
And you and your friend,
Doyle.
Did you hear from him again,
since he left?
Not a word.
He said he was gonna check
the railroad station and the trunk.
He must be still at it.
Something on your mind?
It doesn't make sense to me.
What doesn't?
Women aren't that
unpredictable.
Mmm.
Well, I can't guess
what you're thinking.
A woman has a
favorite handbag
and it always hangs on her bedpost,
where she can get at it easily.
And then, all of a sudden, she goes away
on a trip and leaves it behind. Why?
Because she didn't know
she was going on a trip.
And where she's going,
she wouldn't need the handbag.
Yes, but only her husband
would know that.
And that jewelry.
Women don't keep their
jewelry in a purse
getting all twisted and
scratched and tangled up.
Well, do they hide it
in their husband's clothes?
They do not.
And they don't leave it
behind, either.
Why, a woman going anywhere
but the hospital
would always take makeup,
perfume and jewelry.
Put that over there.
That's inside stuff, huh?
It's basic equipment.
And you don't leave it behind
in your husband's drawer
in your favorite handbag.
Well, I'm with you, sweetie.
I'm with you.
Tom Doyle has a pat answer
for that, though.
That Mrs. Thorwald
left at 6:00 a.m.
yesterday with her husband?
According to those witnesses.
Well, I have a pat
rebuttal for Mr. Doyle.
That couldn't have been Mrs. Thorwald,
or I don't know women.
What about the witnesses?
We'll agree they saw a woman,
but she was not
Mrs. Thorwald.
That is, not yet.
Is that so?
Come here.
I'd like to see your friend's face
when we tell him.
He doesn't sound like
much of a detective.
Oh, don't be too hard on him.
He's a steady worker.
I sure wish he'd show up.
Don't rush him.
We have all night.
- We have all what?
- Night.
I'm going to stay with you.
Well, you'll have to clear that
with my landlord.
I have the whole weekend off.
That's very nice,
but I just have one bed.
If you say anything else,
I'll stay tomorrow night, too.
I won't be able to
give you any pajamas.
You said I'll have to
live out of one suitcase.
I'll bet yours
isn't this small.
This is a suitcase?
Well, a Mark Cross
overnight case, anyway.
Compact, but ample enough.
Looks like you
packed in a hurry.
Look at this.
Isn't that amazing?
I'll trade you...
My feminine intuition
for a bed for the night.
I'll go along with that.
(PIANO PLAYING)
There's that song again.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Where does a man get inspiration
to write a song like that?
Well, he gets it from the landlady
once a month.
It's utterly beautiful.
I wish I could be creative.
Oh, sweetie, you are.
You have a great talent
for creating difficult situations.
- I do?
- Sure.
Like staying here
all night uninvited.
Surprise is the most important
element of attack.
And besides, you're not up
on your private eye literature.
When they're in trouble,
it's always their Girl Friday
who gets them out of it.
Is she the girl that saves them
from the clutches
of the seductive showgirls
and the over-passionate
daughters of the rich?
- The same.
- That's the one, huh?
It's funny. He never ends up
marrying her, does he?
That's strange.
Weird.
Why don't I slip into something
more comfortable?
By all means.
I mean, like the kitchen
and make us some coffee.
Oh, and some
brandy, too, huh?
WOMAN: Harry.
- Jeff.
- Hi.
(LISA HUMMING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
What else have you got
on this man Thorwald?
Well, enough to scare me you wouldn't
show up in time and we'd lose him.
Think he's getting
out of here?
Look, he's got
everything he owns
laid out over there in the bedroom,
waiting to be packed.
I'm just warming some brandy.
Mr. Doyle, I presume?
JEFF: Tom, this is
Miss Lisa Fremont.
How do you do?
We think Thorwald's guilty.
Careful, Tom.
(PHONE RINGING)
- Hello.
- MAN: Lieutenant Doyle.
Yeah, he's right here.
For you.
- Hello.
- Lieutenant Doyle, sir?
Speaking.
Yeah.
All right.
I see. Thank you. Goodbye.
Coffee will be ready soon.
Jeff, aren't you going to tell him
about the jewelry?
Jewelry?
He's got his wife's jewelry hidden
in his clothes in the bedroom over there.
You sure it belonged
to his wife?
It was
in her favorite handbag.
Mr. Doyle, that can only lead
to one conclusion.
Namely?
That it was not Mrs. Thorwald that left
with him yesterday morning.
You figured that out, eh?
Well, it's simply that women don't leave
their jewelry behind
when they go on a trip.
Come on, come on, Tom.
Now you don't really need any
of this information, do you?
As a matter of fact, I don't.
Lars Thorwald is no more
a murderer than I am.
You mean to say you can explain everything
that's gone on over there,
and is still going on?
No, neither can you.
That's a secret, private world
you're looking into out there.
People do a lot of things in private
they couldn't possibly explain in public.
Like disposing
of their wives?
You get that idea out of your mind.
It'll only lead in the wrong direction.
What about the knife
and the saw?
Did you ever own a saw?
Well, at home
in the garage I had...
How many people
did you cut up with it?
Or with the couple of hundred knives
you've probably owned in your lifetime?
Well, your logic is backward.
You can't ignore the wife disappearing
and the trunk and the jewelry.
I checked the railroad station.
He bought a ticket.
Ten minutes later,
he put his wife on a train.
Destination, Merritsville.
The witnesses are that deep.
That might have been a woman,
but it couldn't have been Mrs. Thorwald.
- That jewelry...
- Look, Miss Fremont.
That feminine intuition
stuff sells magazines.
But in real life,
it's still a fairy tale.
I don't know how many
wasted years I've spent
tracking down leads based
on female intuition.
All right. I take it you didn't
find the trunk,
and all this is from an old speech you
once made at the Policemen's Ball.
I found the trunk
a half-hour after I left here.
I suppose it's normal for a man
to tie up a trunk with heavy rope?
Well, if the lock
is broken, yes.
And what did you find inside the trunk?
A surly note to me?
Mrs. Thorwald's clothes.
Clean, well packed.
Not stylish, but presentable.
Didn't you take them
off to the crime lab?
I sent them on their
merry and legal way.
Why, when a woman is taking
a simple, short trip,
does she take everything
she owns?
Let's let the female psychology
department handle that one.
I would say it looked
as if she wasn't coming back.
That's what's known
as a family problem.
And if she wasn't coming back,
why didn't he tell his landlord?
I'll tell you why he didn't tell his landlord.
Because he was hiding something.
Do you tell your
landlord everything?
I told you to
be careful, Tom.
Look, if I'd have been careful piloting
that reconnaissance plane during the war,
you wouldn't have had the chance
to take the pictures
that won you a medal, and a good job,
and fame and money.
What do you say we all sit down
and have a nice, friendly drink, too? Hmm?
Forget all about this.
We can tell lies about the good
old days during the war.
You mean you're through
with the case?
There is no case to be through with,
Miss Fremont.
How about that drink?
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Well, I think I better get home
and get some sleep.
Cheers.
Not much of a snifter.
Oh, Jeff, if you
need any more help...
Consult the Yellow Pages
in your telephone directory.
Oh, I love funny
exiting lines.
Who was that trunk
addressed to?
Mrs. Anna Thorwald.
Well, then let's wait
and find out who picks it up.
Oh, that telephone call.
I gave them your number.
I hope you don't mind.
Depends on who they were.
The police at Merritsville.
They reported the trunk was
just picked up
by Mrs. Anna Thorwald.
Don't stay up too late.
(PEOPLE SINGING)
- Look.
- What?
JEFF: Yeah, he's kind
of young, isn't he?
What are you doing?
(SHOUTING)
(BOTH ARGUING)
You know, much as I hate to give
Thomas J. Doyle too much credit,
he might have gotten a hold
of something when he said
that was pretty private
stuff going on out there.
I wonder if it's ethical to watch a man
with binoculars and a long-focus lens.
Do you... Do you
suppose it's ethical,
even if you prove that he didn't
commit a crime?
I'm not much on
rear-window ethics.
Of course, they can
do the same thing to me.
Watch me like a bug under
a glass, if they want to.
Jeff, you know, if someone came in here,
they wouldn't believe what they'd see.
What?
You and me with long faces.
Plunged into despair because we find out
a man didn't kill his wife.
We're two of the most frightening
ghouls I've ever known.
You'd think we could be a little bit happy
that the poor woman is alive and well.
Whatever happened to that old saying,
"Love thy neighbor"?
(JEFF CHUCKLES)
You know, I think I'll start reviving
that tomorrow.
Yeah, I'll begin
with Miss Torso.
Not if I have to move
into an apartment across the way
and do the Dance of the Seven Veils
every hour.
Show's over for tonight.
Preview of coming
attractions.
Did Mr. Doyle think
I stole this case?
No, Lisa, I don't
think he did.
What do you think?
Well...
I will rephrase the question.
Thank you.
Do you like it?
Yes, I like it.
- (WOMAN SCREAMING)
- Well...
(WOMAN SOBBING)
WOMAN 1: What's the matter?
(CHATTERING)
- MAN 1: Somebody's hurt?
- WOMAN 2: It's the dog.
Something's happened
to the dog.
MAN 2: What's the trouble?
Somebody fall out a window?
MAN 3: See, it's a dog
down there.
It's dead.
It's been strangled.
The neck is broken.
Which one of you did it?
Which one of you
killed my dog?
You don't know the meaning
of the word "Neighbors."
Neighbors like each other,
speak to each other,
care if anybody
lives or dies.
But none of you do!
But I couldn't imagine
any of you being so low
that you'd kill a little
helpless, friendly dog.
The only thing in this whole neighborhood
who liked anybody.
Did you kill him
because he liked you?
Just because he liked you?
Let's go inside.
Come on. Let's go back in.
It's only a dog.
You know, for a minute, that Tom Doyle
almost had me convinced I was wrong.
- But you're not?
- Look.
In the whole courtyard, only one person
didn't come to the window.
Look.
Why would Thorwald want to kill
a little dog?
Because it knew too much?
You think this is worth
waiting all day to see?
LISA: Is he cleaning house?
He's washing down
the bathroom walls.
Hmm.
Must have splattered a lot.
Well, why not?
That's what we're all thinking.
He killed her in there, he has to clean up
those stains before he leaves.
Oh, Stella, your
choice of words.
STELLA: Nobody ever invented
a polite word for a killing yet.
Lisa? Lisa, back there, on that shelf,
there's a little yellow box. You see it?
- Top one?
- Right on top, yeah.
Bring it. And bring
me the viewer there.
I just got a...
Now, these are
about two weeks old.
I hope I took something else besides
eg art. Now which one...
- What are you looking for?
- Here.
There's something, and if I'm right,
I think I've solved a murder.
- Mrs. Thorwald?
- No.
No, the dog.
Uh-huh.
I think I know
why Thorwald killed that dog.
Here, now you take a look.
Tell me what you see.
Now take it down.
Now look again.
Now take it down. You see?
But it's just a picture
of the backyard, that's all.
One important change.
Those flowers in Thorwald's pet
flower bed.
You mean where the dog
was sniffing around?
Where the dog was digging.
Now look at those flowers.
Look, right? Those two yellow
zinnias on this end
aren't as tall as they were.
Now, since when do flowers
grow shorter in two weeks?
There's something
buried there.
Mrs. Thorwald.
You haven't spent much time
around cemeteries, have you?
Mr. Thorwald could scarcely put
his wife's body
in a plot of ground
about one foot square.
Unless, of course, he put her
in standing on end,
and then he wouldn't
need a knife and saw.
No, my idea is she's
scattered all over town.
- Leg in the East River...
- Oh, Stella, please!
No, no, no. There's
something in there.
Those flowers have been taken out
and put back in.
- Maybe it's the knife and saw.
- Yeah.
Call Lieutenant Doyle.
No, let's wait.
Let's wait till it gets a little darker,
and I'll go over there and dig them up.
You'll go? You won't dig anything up
and get your neck broken.
No, no, we've...
We're not gonna call Doyle until
I can produce Mrs. Thorwald's body.
What we've got to do is find
a way to get into that apartment.
He's packing.
Uh-oh.
Here, get me a pencil.
Stella, get me some note paper.
It's up here someplace.
There it is.
You did it, Thorwald.
You did it.
Look out, Lisa. He's coming.
You never should have let her do it.
If he ever...
Look. Look. Look.
(SIGHS)
Well, thank heaven
that's over.
All right if I have a drink?
Sure, go ahead.
There's no doubt about it. He's leaving.
It's just a question of when.
Mind if I use that
portable keyhole?
Go ahead, just as long as you tell me
what you're looking at.
STELLA: I wonder...
JEFF: Wonder what?
Miss Lonelyheart's
just laid out something
that looks like rhodium
tri-eckonal capsules.
You can tell from here?
I've handled enough of those red pills
to put everybody in Hackensack
to sleep for the winter.
Well, does she have
enough of them to...
No. It will make
the rest easy to...
Wasn't that close?
What was his reaction. I mean,
when he looked at the note?
Well, it wasn't the kind of an expression
that would get him a quick loan at the bank.
Jeff, the handbag!
Suppose Mrs. Thorwald's
wedding ring
is among the jewelry
he has in that handbag?
Now, during the phone conversation
he held up three rings.
One with a diamond, one with
a big stone of some sort
and then just
a plain gold band.
And the last thing she would leave behind
would be a wedding ring.
Stella, do you ever
leave yours at home?
The only way anybody could get that ring
would be to chop off my finger.
Let's go down and find out
what's buried in the garden.
Why not? I've always wanted
to meet Mrs. Thorwald.
- What are you two talking about?
- You got a shovel?
A shovel? Of course
I don't have a shovel.
There's probably
one in the basement.
Jeff, if you're squeamish,
just don't look.
Squeamish? I'm not squeamish.
I just don't want you two to end up
like that dog ended up. That's all.
Oh, you know, Miss Fremont,
he might just have something there.
Just hold on.
Here, take this.
No sense taking any
chances in this thing.
Here, give me the phone book.
What for?
Maybe I can get him
out of that apartment.
We only need a few minutes.
I'll see if I can
get about 15 minutes.
How?
Thorwald.
Thorwald... Thorwald...
Chelsea 27099.
27099.
We scared him once,
maybe we can scare him again.
Well, I guess I'm using that word
"we" a little freely.
I mean, you're taking
all the chances.
LISA: Shall we vote
him in, Stella?
STELLA: Unanimously.
27099. Look out.
Chelsea.
(PHONE RINGING)
Go on, pick it up, Thorwald.
Go on, you're curious.
You wonder if it's your girlfriend calling,
the one you killed for.
Go on, pick it up.
THORWALD: Hello?
Did you get my note?
Well, did you get it,
Thorwald?
Who are you?
I'll give you a chance
to find out.
Meet me in the bar
at the Albert Hotel.
Do it right away.
Why should I?
A little business meeting...
To settle the estate
of your late wife.
I don't know what you mean.
Come on. Quit stalling, Thorwald,
or I'll hang up and call the police.
I have only $100 or so.
That's a start.
I'm at the Albert now.
I'll be looking for you.
Come on, Stella, let's go.
One of you keep an eye
on this window.
If I see him coming back,
I'll signal with a flashbulb.
WOMAN: This is
the Doyle residence.
Hello, this is L.B. Jefferies speaking.
I'm a friend of Mr. Doyle.
Who's this?
This is a babysitter.
Oh. Uh...
When do you expect them in?
Well, I'm hired till 1:00. They went
to dinner and maybe a nightclub.
I see.
If he calls in, would you have him get
in touch with L.B. Jefferies right away?
I might have quite
a surprise for him.
Well, do we have your number,
Mr. Jefferies?
He has it. Good night.
Good night.
JEFF: Stella was wrong
about Miss Lonelyheart.
(INAUDIBLE)
Lisa, what are you...
Don't do...
Lisa, what are you
doing? Don't go...
Come on, come on!
Get out of there!
She said ring Thorwald's phone
the second you see him come back.
I'm gonna ring it right now!
Oh, no. Give her
another minute.
MAN: All right, fellows, let's try it
once from the beginning.
Miss Lonelyheart.
Oh, call the police!
WOMAN: Operator.
Get me the police,
sixth precinct.
Yes, sir.
STELLA: Mr. Jefferies,
the music stopped her.
What... Lisa!
Lisa!
Precinct 6, Sergeant Allgood.
Hello. Hello. Look, a man is assaulting
a woman at 125 West 9th Street.
Second floor, at the rear.
Make it fast!
Your name?
L.B. Jefferies.
Phone number?
Chelsea 25598.
(INAUDIBLE)
The door was open.
(CHATTERING)
- I told you...
- Oh, no!
Let go of me! Jeff!
Oh, no!
LISA: Jeff! Jeff!
Jeff!
Lisa!
Stella, what do we do?
Jeff!
- Jeff!
- STELLA: Well, here they come.
(SIGHS)
(INAUDIBLE)
STELLA: What's she trying to do?
Why doesn't she turn him in?
She's a smart girl.
"Smart girl"?
She'll get herself arrested.
It'll get her out
of there, won't it?
Look, the wedding ring!
Turn off the light!
He's seen us!
How long do you think
he'll stay there?
Well, unless he's dumber than I think he is,
he won't wait until his lease is up.
Get my billfold out of the drawer
in the table there.
What do you need money for?
I'm gonna bail
Lisa out of jail.
You know, you could leave her
there till next Tuesday,
then you could sneak
safely away as planned.
Yeah, let's see. $127.
How much do you need?
Well, this is first-offense burglary,
that's about $250.
- Lisa's handbag.
- Yeah.
How much does she have?
Fifty cents.
Here, take this.
Look, I got $20 or so
in my purse.
What about the rest?
When those cops see Lisa,
they'll even contribute.
Well, hurry up.
(PHONE RINGING)
Just a minute. Hurry up!
Jefferies.
DOYLE: All right.
What is it now?
Doyle, I've got
something really big for you.
Why did I have to
return your call?
Look, Jeff! Don't louse up my night
with another mad killer...
Listen to me! Listen to me!
Lisa's in jail. She got arrested.
- Your Lisa?
- My Lisa.
Boy, you should have seen her.
She got into Thorwald's apartment.
But then he came back, and the only way
I could get her out was to call the police.
- I told you...
- I know you told me!
She went in to get evidence
and she came out with evidence.
- Like what?
Like Mrs. Thorwald's wedding ring.
That's like what.
If that woman was alive,
she'd be wearing that ring. Right?
- A possibility.
- A possibility. It's a fact!
He killed a dog last night because the dog was
scratching around in the garden.
You know why? Because he had something buried
in that garden that the dog scented.
Like an old ham bone?
Look, I don't know what pet names
Thorwald had for his wife,
but I'll tell you this,
all those trips at night
with that metal suitcase,
he wasn't taking
out his possessions,
because his possessions
are still up in the apartment.
Perhaps it was
old "ham bone."
Yeah, in sections.
And I'll tell you
something else.
All the telephone calls he made were
long distance, all right?
Now, if he called his wife
long distance on the day she left,
after she arrived
in Merritsville,
why did she write a card to him saying that
she'd arrived in Merritsville?
Why did she do that?
Where'd they take Lisa?
Precinct 6.
I sent somebody over
with the bail money.
Maybe you won't need it.
I'll run it down, Jeff.
All right. All right.
Now hurry up, will you?
This fellow knows
he's being watched.
He's not gonna wait
around forever. Hurry up.
If that ring checks out,
we'll give him an escort.
- So long, Jeff.
- So long.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello. Hello. Tom, I think
Thorwald's left. I don't see...
Hello...
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
What do you want from me?
Your friend, the girl,
could have turned me in.
Why didn't she?
What is it you want? A lot of money?
I don't have any money.
Say something.
Say something!
Tell me what you want!
Can you get me
that ring back?
No.
Tell her to bring it back!
I can't. The police
have it by now.
Lisa! Doyle!
WOMAN: Over there!
Look! Look, over
in that apartment!
JEFF: Doyle!
Creele! Give me your .38!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
I'm sorry, Jeff.
I got here as fast as I could!
Oh, Mr. Jefferies!
Don't let anybody touch him.
Get my medical bag
from upstairs.
Oh, Lisa, sweetie,
if anything had happened to you...
Oh, shut up. I'm all right.
Gee, I'm proud of you!
You got enough for
a search warrant now?
Oh, yeah, sure.
- DETECTIVE: Lieutenant Doyle!
- Yeah?
Is he okay?
He's alive.
Thorwald's ready to take us
on a tour of the East River.
Did he say what was
buried in the flower bed?
Yeah. He said the dog got
too inquisitive, so he dug it up.
It's in a hat box over
in his apartment.
- Want to look?
- No, thanks.
I don't want any part of her.
I hope it's gonna be a hit.
This is the first release.
I'd love to hear it.
I can't tell you what this music
has meant to me.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN: (SINGING)
Lisa, with your starry eyes
Now, let's try
it again, puppy.
Stay still. Stay.
Hold me and whisper the sweet words
I'm yearning for
Drown me in kisses
- Stanley!
- Hi, baby!
Caresses I'm burning for
My, look what the Army's done
for you!
Lisa, every touch is
new ecstasy
The Army's made me hungry.
What've you got in the icebox to eat?
Boy, it's good to be home.
Lisa, angels dance
when you cling to me
I don't care
if you help me or not,
but if you'd told me you'd quit your job,
we wouldn't have gotten married.
Oh, honey, come on...
If this is dreaming
I hope I'll never wake
But dream forever
In your arms, oh, Lisa
Lisa